ALEKSA TEŠIĆ

 P Belgrade, Serbia
 ☑ aleksatesicteske@gmail.com
 ☑ (+381) 60 424 37 69
 ☑ github.com/Imafikus

ABOUT

Software engineer experienced in building and maintaining everything from CI/CD pipelines and deployments to application frontends. Always programming something. Currently mostly interested in software architecture and design. Record collector and Warhammer enthusiast. Big fan of stoner rock and a guitar player.

SKILLS

ACTIVELY USING / USED	HAD SOME EXPERIENCE	COLLABORATION
TS/JS	R	Git
Python, Flask, Selenium	С	Jira
React + Tailwind	C++	Confluence
Node + Express	Java	
Terraform, GCP	Pascal	
Bash, Github Actions	Haskell	
Postgres, MongoDB	Angular	
Ansible, Vagrant		
Docker, Jenkins		
K8s, Helm		

WORK EXPERIENCE

Devops Engineer - Connect the Dots (September 2021 - present)

Worked on migration from docker based setup to GKE. Integrated tracing accross all microservices in order to pinpoint performance pain points. Implemented new and improved existing CI / CD Github Actions pipelines. Deployed and improved existing IaC setup via Terraform.

Main technologies used: Terrafom, K8s, GCP, Github Actions, Typescript, Python

Notify Me - Co-Founder (October 2018 - present)

 $Notify \, Me \, aims \, to \, change \, the \, way \, people \, track \, sites \, by \, providing \, them \, with \, meaningful \, changes \, and \, not \, just \, simple \, diffs.$

Developed the first version of the site completely on my own. Currently leading a team of 5. Main thing I'm working on right now is the complete FE development via React + Tailwind, Project Management for the whole team, setting up of CI /CD pipelines and rewritting BE in order to integrate new data pipelines.

Main technologies used: Python, Flask, Selenium, Terrafom, GCP, React, Tailwind

notify-me.rs

Associate in Petnica (September 2017 - present)

Attended CS course for 3 years and then stayed there as a junior assistant on both CS and TEH departments. Organized and held lectures from various CS fields and helped attendees with their summer projects. I'm currently working as head of TEH department and as a technical associate on CS department. Current work consists of planning yearly course cycles and managing a team of ~10 junior assistants and organizing guest lectures from people relevant to the STEM field.

Junior Devops Engineer - Itekako (September 2020 - June 2021)

Worked on various services for different customers. Most of the work was done on bare metal machines which were fully set up via Ansible while local development used Vagrant. Most notable project I worked on included completely automating deployment workflow for Node.js based app written for AtlasCopco. Apart from that, various smaller tasks were done via mostly bash and / or Python scripts. Part of the job also included technical support for the development team of Itekako.

Main technologies used: Ansible, Vagrant, Bash, Python, Docker, Jenkins

Junior Backend Engineer - Penta Fintech (March 2019 - August 2020)

Started in Cards team whose main task was ensuring smooth communication with our banking provider - SolarisBank. Core responsibilities were implementation of business logic and integrations with various smaller providers. Apart from that, major part of the job was refactoring old ES5 Javascript code into ES6 Typescript while, at the same time, breaking down monolith based code into smaller services and improving test coverage. In the last few months of my employment at Penta I was transfered to the BackOffice team whose main task was ensuring that our internal CRM app worked properly.

Main technologies used: Node + Express, Postgres, Typescript

Upwork / Freelancing (December 2017 - March 2019)

Mostly worked on smaller python based projects with some HTML here and there. Stopped when I joined Penta, since working 2 jobs and going to faculty just wasn't possible.

Main technologies used: Python, HTML

EDUCATION

University of Belgrade, Faculty of Mathematics (2017 - 2021)

 $Department \, of \, Computer \, Science \, \hbox{-}\, Informatics \, BSc$

Random Github

 $Random\ github\ comments\ every\ day.\ Simple\ service\ which\ will\ fetch\ comments\ for\ today's\ trending\ github\ repos\ and\ it\ will\ display\ one\ random\ comment\ on\ user\ request.\ Backend\ is\ written\ using\ FastAPI,\ while\ frontend\ used\ Next.js.$

Main technologies used: Python, React

randomgithub.com

Chat System

 $Simple \ real-time\ chat\ app\ which\ supports\ groups.\ Chat\ history\ is\ stored\ in\ memory.\ Made\ as\ a\ part\ of\ Computer\ Networks\ course\ on\ faculty.$

Main technologies used: React, Node + Express, Socket.io, Typescript

Github Link

Vehicle autopilot using fuzzy controllers and metaheuristics

Optimization of the fuzzy parameters for the fuzzy system. Fuzzy system was controlling the vehicle, and the goal was to improve the controls via GA. Finished project was a car agent who knew how to drive a specific race track via rules set by fuzzy system and then optimized via GA.

Main technologies used: Python, Genetic Algorithms, Fuzzy Systems

Github Link

Google Form generator

Created a language which enables you to make a Google Form from a specific file. Removes the need to manually copy paste a bunch of the same types of form elements. Made for TEH department in Petnica.

Main technologies used: Python

Github Link

Other projects are also located on my GitHub page, altough not all of them are public.